#### Contact

cjames19@protonmail.ch

www.linkedin.com/in/cjamesni (LinkedIn) cjamesni.github.io (Personal) www.youracclaim.com/users/

### Top Skills

cjamesni (Other)

Swift

**Python** 

Bash

#### Certifications

200-125 CCNA: Routing and Switching

Splunk Certified User

Jamf CCA: Certified Casper Administrator

Jamf CCT: Certified Casper Technician

#### Honors-Awards

CME Group Excellence Award, October 2016

CME Group Excellence Award, July 2017

CME Group Excellence Award, August 2017

# **Christopher James**

IT Systems Engineer, CCNA United Kingdom

## Summary

Professional summary:

IT Systems engineer with 5+ years of experience in working with enterprise IT infrastructure and services. Specialises in IT system administration, engineering, deployment and automation. Special interests include: unix, linux & macOS internals, network routing & switching and automation software.

Key skills & experience:

- System administration of Unix and Linux environments supporting: \*nix operating systems, Bash and Python.
- System administration and engineering of Apple desktop hardware and software applications for enterprise including: macOS, Xcode, Instruments, Bash, Python, Swift and Jamf Pro.
- Network administration and network monitoring for enterprise including: a strong working knowledge of common network infrastructure and network protocol (CCNA, N+ and Splunk certified).
- Endpoint system security management including: CVE review, vulnerability remediation, OS hardening, user access & application control.
- Co-leading management of a global staff device collection and coordinating global operating system deployment projects.
- Client application packaging and scripting for macOS & iOS. Client application code-signing and enterprise distribution for macOS & iOS.
- Web application support and development including: customisation, configuration and deployment of a modern enterprise web service (VPC hosted with SSO and 2FA access) with supporting open source API connection components written in Python, deploying solution components to QA & Production enterprise environments.
- Version control using Git, GitHub and Bitbucket: https:// cjamesni.github.io (My personal GitHub site)
- System engineering experience working with AWS hosted solutions supporting: AWS CLI, NGINX+, EC2 and RDS.

Some favourite quotes:

"Ever tried. Ever failed. No matter. Try again. Fail again. Fail better." Beckett

"Allons travailler!" (Get on with it!) Zola

## Experience

**CME** Group

4 years

Desktop Engineer III, Global Desktop & IT Infrastructure Services December 2017 - Present (2 years 3 months)

Belfast, United Kingdom

- Primarily focused on delivering systems administration and systems engineering tasks for global desktop environments and IT infrastructure at CME Group.
- Specifically responsible for co-leading the management of a large staff device collection spanning the US, Europe and Asia, adopting a 'security first' approach.
- Standardising team processes and writing technical documentation.
- Research & development for individual and team projects.

Desktop Engineer II, Global Desktop & IT Infrastructure Services March 2016 - December 2017 (1 year 10 months)

Belfast, United Kingdom

- Endpoint System Solutions Group member delivering systems support and systems engineering functions at CME Group.
- Escalation point for members of the internal customer support group locally and globally.
- Collaborating with teams from the Infrastructure & Operations department to remediate incidents of network, system or application(s) downtime.
- Managing endpoint system security, including: CVE review, vulnerability remediation, OS hardening, user access and application control.
- Co-ordinating global OS deployment projects, including: Jira based issue and task tracking, creation and maintenance of Epics, Stories, Dashboards and Sprints.
- Preparing macOS application packages, scripts, security and system updates for global distribution.
- Managing and assigning site assets.

Cobalt Technology

# Infrastructure Engineer II, Managed IT Services, Europe & CIS January 2015 - March 2016 (1 year 3 months)

Citywest Business Campus, Dublin, Ireland

- Disaster recovery operations including monitoring the back-up and replication of virtual machines from customer-owned production environments to a managed secondary site (using VMware vSphere 5.5 and Veeam B&R 7). Managing snapshots and restarting failed replication jobs.
- Escalating significant back-up and replication issues to senior infrastructure engineers.
- Updating back-levelled firmware on IBM storage systems and collecting DSA system logs for vendor diagnostics as required.
- Systems administration for hybrid Microsoft environments using PowerShell and Windows server administration tools.
- Managing client Active Directory forests including OU, security group, user and computer objects.
- -Managing client GPOs via Group Policy Management Editor.
- Lync server administration of online and enterprise voice users. Assigning telephone DDIs.
- Implementing Lync server QoS to improve communication quality.
- Exchange server administration. Managing user mailbox assignment, distribution groups and global address lists. Setting up Unified Exchange Messaging services.
- Managing SharePoint site collections. Provisioning site storage and structuring SharePoint sites including subsites, libraries, lists and applications.
- Troubleshooting and reporting on managed IT services for customers. Liaising with third parties to resolve problems.
- Supporting client's LAN networks.

### Teleperformance

Technical Support Advisor, Samsung Electronics, UK Customer Services

September 2012 - December 2014 (2 years 4 months)

Quays Complex, Newry, United Kingdom

- Two years plus contact centre experience with the Teleperformance Group working as a technical support advisor for their client company, Samsung Electronics UK.
- Responsible for administering technical services and troubleshooting support for consumers of Samsung multimedia electronics products across the UK.
- Managing system configurations, hardware diagnostics, software updates and system recoveries.

- Explaining technical instructions to consumers via telephone, email and social media.

Norbrook Laboratories Itd Laboratory Technician, Norbrook Laboratories Ltd, UK April 2009 - September 2009 (6 months) Camlough Road, Newry, United Kingdom

- Six months work experience as a Lab Technician based within Norbrook Laboratories Microbiology Department. I was responsible for reading and recording test data onto company paperwork, creating batch reports and updating company databases.

## Education

The Open University

Top-up Bachelor of Science (Honours), Computing and Information Technology (2020)

**Ulster University** 

Foundation, Information and Communication Technology · (2013)

Abbey Christian Brothers' Grammar School (2008)